Let's get started with day five for the month of September.
Hi, everyone. I'm Steve Sareisi.
英語でつながる船の旅
We're cruising around the Atlantic Ocean.
そして今月はスコットランドが舞台です。
ということで早速あなたの会話パートナーを呼びましょう。
ノラさんです。
Hi, everyone. I'm Nora Kennedy.
Let's go to Scotland together. We'll have fun conversations there.
Welcome back to A Kiowa Time Trial, Nora.
Great to be back.
So, originally you're from Ireland. We're talking about Scotland.
Have you been to Scotland before?
Yes. Scotland has fantastic Scotch whisky, beautiful mountains and hills,
and, of course, castles and great universities.
So, is it easy to go from Ireland to Scotland?
Sure, it's about a one-hour flight.
I see.
では、さっそく始めましょう。
Here we go!
対話カラオケ
Around the Atlantic
ラジオを通して英語で模擬会話をしましょう。
今月の学習テーマを覚えていますか?
Dress for Success in Scotland
衣服や服装にまつわる会話に挑戦しましょう。
So, let's check out today's scene.
今日の会話の場面を確認しましょう。
Picture this.
You're going to a world famous lake in Scotland.
It's called Loch Ness.
あなたは今日スコットランドの有名な湖、
ネスコに散策に出かけます。
I'll show you around Loch Ness.
I'll be your guide.
散策ガイドの野良さんがネスコを案内してくれます。
The autumn leaves are breathtaking.
It's one of the most beautiful scenes in northern Europe.
But the weather can change easily.
紅葉が美しい季節ですが、天気が目まぐるしく変わる時期でもあります。
It's a little chilly.
And it might rain at any time.
So, we'll talk about proper clothes for the weather, too.
天気や服装などについてガイドの野良さんと会話をしましょう。
Did you picture the situation?
それでは、野良さんの英語の問いかけに対してポーズの間に返答しましょう。
自由回答です。
So, try to have a six-turn conversation as we walk around Loch Ness.
Ready? Start!
Welcome to Scotland's famous Loch Ness.
Beautiful lake, isn't it?
This might be the most beautiful autumn scene in Europe.
Oh, a little rain is coming.
Well, I have ponchos for everyone.
レインコートを用意してくれたようです。
一言返しましょう。
9月にしては暖かいですねと言われました。
答えましょう。
Is Japan cold in September?
Well, I get cold easily, so I wore lots of layers today.
Do you know what I mean by layers?
Layers.
Let's answer as we please.
I'm wearing my leggings and my undershirt.
Now I'm a little hot and feel overdressed.
Do you get cold easily?
How did you do?
Did you reply each time?
You don't have to reply every time.
この後もう一度挑戦します。
その前に少しノラさんと天気について話しましょう。
So, Nora, at this time of the year,
how's the weather in Scotland and Ireland?
Well, the truth is it could be terrible.
It's totally unpredictable.
I see.
Totally.
全くunpredictable.
予測できません。
天気が変わりやすい時期ですね。
それでは、
Nora-san to boku de kyou no kaiwa wo shite mimasu.
Boku no hento wo cheku shite, sanko ni shite mite kudasai.
Steve will show you one way to reply.
Here we go!
Welcome to Scotland's famous Loch Ness.
Beautiful lake, isn't it?
Yeah. The autumn leaves are so colorful now.
This might be the most beautiful autumn scene in Europe.
Oh, a little rain is coming.
Well, I have ponchos for everyone.
Here's a poncho for you.
Thanks, but I brought a foldable umbrella.
Thanks anyway.
Oh, the rain has stopped and the sun is out.
It's warm for September, isn't it?
Yeah, it's not too cold today.
Is Japan cold in September?
Not really. It's getting cold. But usually, we have nice, warm, sunny fall weather.
Well, I get cold easily. So, I wore lots of layers today. Do you know what I mean by layers?
I think so. In Japanese, layering is kasanegi. Most people wear layers in winter.
I'm wearing my leggings and my undershirt.
Now, I'm a little hot and feel overdressed. Do you get cold easily?
Yes, I do. I get cold very easily. I'm always cold, so I always wear layers.
Okay, did you understand our conversation?
So, let's try again today's Mogi conversation.
Please try to give your own answer.
do your best everyone ready
start
welcome to Scotland's famous Loch Ness
beautiful lake isn't it this might be
the most beautiful autumn scene in Europe
Oh, a little rain is coming. Well, I have ponchos for everyone. Here's a poncho for you.
Oh, the rain has stopped and the sun is out. It's warm for September, isn't it?
Is Japan cold in September?
Well, I get cold easily, so I wore lots of layers today.
Do you know what I mean by layers?
I'm wearing my leggings and my undershirt.
Now I'm a little hot and feel overdressed.
Do you get cold easily?
Time's up.
Did you reply each time and complete our conversation?
Great job this week.
さて、来週はスコットランドならではの衣装、キルトについて話しましょう。
Let's talk about Scotland's national dress, the kilt.
So everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on Eikaiwa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.