Let's get started with Day 10 for the month of September.
Hi, everyone. I'm Steve Seresi.
And here's our conversation partner around the Atlantic.
Hello, everyone. I'm Nora Kennedy.
Let's have a conversation in Scotland this month.
Okay, everyone. Here we go.
Taiwa Harake. Around the Atlantic.
英語でつながる船の旅
今月はスコットランドを訪れます
そして今月の学習テーマは
Dress for success in Scotland
それでは今日の会話の場面を確認しましょう
Picture this
Today you will rent something very Scottish
A kilt
Next week you're going to a special event
So, today, rent a Scottish outfit.
あなたは来週特別なイベントに行くことになったので、
今日はスコットランドの伝統衣装、キルトをレンタルすることにしました。
Go to a rental clothing store. I will be working there.
So, tell me your size.
店員さんの野田さんに普段着る服のサイズなどを伝えましょう。
You can try the clothes on.
So, let's find the right Scottish outfit for you.
着ると試着できるようなので、着心地などを伝えましょう。
Did you picture the situation?
それでは、野良さんの英語の問いかけに対して、ポーズの間に英語で返答しましょう。
So, try to have an eight-turn conversation as you get a Scottish outfit.
Ready? Start!
Welcome to Atlantic Kilt Rental. How can I help you?
Let me tell you that I want to rent a kilt.
OK. And the kilt will be for you, right?
Are you going to an event, some special occasion?
Okay. How tall are you?
Well, are your clothes usually large, medium, small or petite?
Hmm.
This outfit might look good on you.
Sure. The fitting room is over there.
How does it feel? Too tight? Too loose?
May I take a look?
Oh, it fits pretty well.
And it looks good on you.
Look in this mirror.
試着した自分の姿を想像して感想を一言伝えましょう。
Time's up.
How did you do?
Did you reply to each one?
How much did you answer?
Well then, Nora-san and I will have a conversation.
Please check my answer and use it as reference.
Steve will show you one way to reply.
Here we go!
Welcome to Atlantic Kilt Rental.
How can I help you?
I'd like to rent a kilt.
Okay.
And the kilt will be for you, right?
that's right I hope you have my size
are you going to an event some special occasion
yes I'm going to a nice afternoon
T and I need to dress for success
okay how tall are you in centimeters
I'm 170 centimeters tall
I'm not sure how many inches that is well
Are your clothes usually a large, medium, small, or petite?
Usually, I wear a large for t-shirts or dress shirts.
But sometimes I wear a medium.
Hmm. This outfit might look good on you.
Okay. Is it okay if I try on this one?
Sure. The fitting room is over there.
How does it feel?
Too tight? Too loose?
It feels a little loose, but not too loose.
It feels nice and warm.
May I take a look?
Oh, it fits pretty well.
And it looks good on you.
Look in this mirror.
Wow! I like it.
Hello.
Okay.
Did you understand our conversation?
さて、僕がどのように答えたか少し内容を確認しましょう。
例えば、
Are you going to an event? Some special occasion?
それに対して僕は、
Yes, I'm going to a nice afternoon tea.
と言ってましたね。
そしてその後、
I need to dress for success.
成功させるためにちゃんとした服を着たいです。
そして一番最後に自分がキルと来た感想を伝える場面がありましたね。
せっかくなので感情を込めて言いましょう。
僕は、
Wow! I like it!
そして最後にスコットランドなどで聞く、
Hello! を言いました。
How would you say that, Nora?
Hello!
そのようなスパイスを入れてもOKです。
それでは最後にもう一度今日の模擬会話に挑戦です。
自分なりのヘントできるかどうかチャレンジしてください。
Do your best, everyone. Ready, start!
Welcome to Atlantic Kilt Rental. How can I help you?
Okay, and the kilt will be for you, right?
Are you going to an event, some special occasion?
Okay, how tall are you?
Well, how tall are you?
Are your clothes usually large, medium, small, or petite?
Hmm...
This outfit might look good on you.
Sure.
The fitting room is over there.
How does it feel?
Too tight?
Too loose?
May I take a look?
Oh, it fits pretty well.
And it looks good on you.
Look in this mirror.
Time's up.
Okay. You did much better the second time.
Well done.
来週の金曜日はキルトを着て
ロラさんと素敵なイベント
アフトヌーンティーに参加します。
That sounds wonderful.
I'm really looking forward to it.
I love a nice afternoon tea.
Okay, everyone. Get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on Ekaiba Time Trial.
Bye-bye.