A Kiowa Time Trial
Let's get started with Day 14 for the month of September.
Hi, everyone. I'm Steve Ceresi.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore. Thanks for joining us.
It's Thursday. Let's practice the phrases we learned this week.
And we'll get you ready for actual conversations.
All right, let's get started.
Express. Create. Reply.
Hi.
First, let's do some warming up.
Step 1. Express.
Ima kara Jenny-san ga konshuu rinshu shita hyougen o
random ni itte kuremasu no de
nani mo minai de zembu ripiito dekiru ka
challenge shite mite kudasai.
And copy my intonation.
Okay, here we go.
Where did you get that outfit?
Actually, I'm renting this outfit.
It's heavier than I expected.
I love that plaid scarf.
Do you wear plaid often?
I almost never wear plaid.
All right. Did you express all those phrases quickly and smoothly?
And now, let's move on to the next step.
Step 2. Create.
Let's create some original sentences with the phrases that we practiced this week.
Here's the first phrase.
〜何々を着るのが好きです。
I like to wear something.
So, think about a pattern, like stripes or polka dots, or a color, light blue or dark
blue, for example, and then make a sentence about the clothes that you like to wear.
Are you ready?
I like to wear...
Go ahead.
Good.
So, let's hear what Jenny likes to wear.
I like to wear colorful outfits.
I see.
Okay, everyone.
Make one more sentence with the phrase,
I like to wear 〜.
Here we go.
Very good.
Now let's go to the second phrase.
〜には似合いません。
〜don'tあるいは doesn't look good on me.
And again, you can think about a pattern or a color
that doesn't look good on you.
では部分を作りましょう。
〜don't doesn't look good on me.
Go ahead.
Okay, Jenny, it's your turn.
Polka dots don't look good on me.
I see.
Now let's make one more sentence.
〜don't, doesn't look good on me.
Go ahead.
Alright, let's go to the next one.
その〜はすごくかわいいですね。
That 〜 is adorable.
Adorable.
とてもかわいい。
すごくかわいい。
相手が身につけているものについて文を作りましょう。
Are you ready?
That 〜 is adorable.
Go ahead.
Okay, let's check out Jenny's sentence.
That backpack is adorable.
Can you imagine a very cute backpack?
Backpackはリュックサックのことですね。
Okay, try to make one more sentence with the phrase,
That 〜 is adorable.
Go ahead.
Okay, now let's move on to our final step.
Step 3. Reply.
I'll ask a question in English, and you reply in English.
Here's the first question.
あなたは着物をよく着るか聞きますよ。
Do you wear a kimono often?
And you can start with yes, no, or well, but then add one sentence.
Try to explain yourself. Are you ready?
Do you wear a kimono often?
Go ahead.
Very good.
では、返答例を聞きましょう。
Do you wear a kimono often?
Not really.
I just wear them for special occasions like weddings.
Jenny didn't say yes or no.
She said, not really.
And then, I just wear them for special occasions like weddings.
All right.
Try to answer this question one more time.
Do you wear a kimono often?
Good.
Let's go to the next question.
あなたが今着ている服について、それをどこで買ったか聞きます。
Where did you get that outfit?
Maybe it was a present, or maybe you bought it somewhere.
Try to explain in your own words.
Are you ready?
Where did you get that outfit?
Go ahead.
Alright.
Let's check out the sample reply.
Where did you get that outfit?
I got this plaid scarf in Japan, but I almost never wear plaid.
I got it just for my trip to Scotland.
Did you understand?
Jenny is imagining she is wearing a plaid scarf.
Plaid.
Chekkagara.
Scarf is mafra.
So she says, I got this plaid scarf in Japan.
That's the answer.
OK, let's try this question one more time.
Are you ready?
Where did you get that outfit?
And now, let's go to the final question.
今月の舞台、スコットランドならではのシチュエーションです。
あなたが参加しているイベントで
バグパイプの演奏が始まります
Have you ever seen a bagpipe?
It's a traditional Scottish instrument
そこで僕があなたに
バグパイプの演奏を聞いた感想を聞きます
What do you think of the bagpipes?
さあ、感想を伝えましょう
いきますよ
What do you think of the bagpipes?
Go ahead
では、返答例を聞きましょう。
Let's check a sample reply.
What do you think of the bagpipes?
I've only seen bagpipes on TV.
I've never seen them in person like this.
It's magnificent.
その演奏が素晴らしいと言いたいとき、
It's そしてGreat Wonderful あるいはジェニーさんが
Magnificent と言いましたね。
壮大ですねのようなニュアンス。
All right, I'll ask this question one more time.
Here we go.
What do you think of the bagpipes?
Okay, time's up.
Great job today, everyone.
All right, and tomorrow we have Taiwa Karaoke.
You're going to an afternoon tea in Scotland.
And of course, you'll be talking about some special outfits.
Because you're going to dress up.
Try to use the phrases that we practiced this week.
So everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
Eikaiwa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.