A Kiowa Time Trial
Let's get started with Day 15 for the month of September.
Hi, everyone. I'm Steve Sarese.
Hello, everyone. I'm Nora Kennedy.
Try to complete a conversation with me today in your own words.
Okay, everyone. Let's finish up this month.
It's time for...
Kiowa Parake
Around the Atlantic
英語でつながる船の旅
あなたは今月スコットランドに来ています
そして今月の学習テーマは
Dress for success in Scotland
That's right
Dress for success
今日はドレスアップしますよ
前回の対話カラオケで
スコットランドの伝統衣装
キルトをレンタルしましたが
今日はそれを着て
特別な場所に行きますよ
So
Here's today's scene. Picture this.
Today, you are going to an afternoon tea in a castle.
あなたは今日、お城で開かれるアフタヌーンティーに参加することになりました。
This afternoon tea is a little formal.
And so, you've dressed up in a traditional Scottish outfit, a kilt.
And I'll be there in a kimono.
今回のアフターヌーンティーは少しフォーマルな内容なので、あなたはキルトを着ていきます。
ノラさんはなんと着物で参加するようですよ。
Picture me in a kimono, and let's talk about it.
And picture yourself talking about your outfit too.
お互いの服装について会話を弾ませましょう。
Did you picture the situation?
それでは、野良さんの英語の問いかけに対して、ポーズの間に声に出して英語で返答しましょう。
So, try to have a six-turn conversation as we are dressed for success in Scotland.
Ready? Start!
Well, look at you! You wore a Scottish outfit, and I wore a Japanese outfit.
野良さんの着物姿を褒めて、どこで手に入れたのか尋ねましょう。
どうぞ。
I love this kimono.
I got it in Japan.
Actually, my homestay family kindly gave it to me.
Do you wear a kimono often?
Well, your Scottish outfit looks great.
Where did you get that outfit?
あなたの着るとはどこで手に入れたのか聞かれました。
答えましょう。
You'll fit in with the locals in Scotland.
And I love that plaid scarf.
Where did you get it?
That's perfect for today's afternoon tea at the castle.
By the way, do you go to Japanese tea ceremonies often?
日本ではお茶会によく行くか聞かれました。
自分なりにどうぞ。
Oh!
We have a bagpipe performance.
What do you think?
Kansou wo sutai mashou.
Time's up.
How many times did you reply?
Well, Nora, we're talking about afternoon tea in Scotland.
Have you been to an afternoon tea in Ireland?
Yes, and I've been to afternoon tea in England, in London, for example.
It's a lovely thing to do.
How about tea ceremonies in Japan?
Yes, well, I've lived in Japan for quite a long time.
So I've been to a number of tea ceremonies in Japan.
All right, last question.
Tell me your favorite kind of Japanese tea.
I'll go first.
Do you like hojicha?
I like genmai-cha.
Oh, I like that one too!
Yeah, it's got a lot of character.
Steve will show you one way to reply.
Here we go!
Well, look at you!
You wore a Scottish outfit.
and I wore a Japanese outfit that kimono looks great on you
so tell me about that kimono where did you get it
I love this kimono I got it in Japan
actually my homestay family kindly gave it to me
do you wear a kimono often not really
I just wear them for special occasions like weddings well
Your Scottish outfit looks great. Where did you get that outfit?
Thanks. Actually, I'm renting this outfit. I wanted to fit in with the locals.
You'll fit in with the locals in Scotland. And I love that plaid scarf. Where did you get it?
Actually, I got this scarf in Japan. But I almost never wear plaid. I got this just for my trip to Scotland.
That's perfect for today's afternoon tea at the castle.
By the way, do you go to Japanese tea ceremonies often?
I've never been.
My mom goes to tea ceremonies, though.
Oh, we have a bagpipe performance.
What do you think?
I've only seen bagpipes on TV.
I've never seen them in person like this.
It's magnificent.
Okay, did you understand our conversation?
Finally, let's try again today's Mogi conversation.
Instead of answering the same way as my reply,
please challenge yourself to see if you can do your own reply.
Do your best, everyone.
Ready, start!
Well, look at you!
You wore a Scottish outfit.
And I wore a Japanese outfit.
I love this kimono.
I got it in Japan.
Actually, my homestay family kindly gave it to me.
Do you wear a kimono often?
Well, your Scottish outfit looks great.
Where did you get that outfit?
You'll fit in with the locals in Scotland.
And I love that plaid scarf.
Where did you get it?
That's perfect for today's afternoon tea at the castle.
By the way, do you go to Japanese tea ceremonies often?
Oh, we have a bagpipe performance.
What do you think?
Thank you.
OK, time's up.
Did you reply each time and complete our conversation?
Well done, everyone.
会話を自分の言葉で完成させましたか?
さて、スコットランドの旅はここまでとなりますが、
今月はもう一週間特別なトレーニングがあります。
Special week.
あなたの英語の瞬発力をさらにアップさせていきましょう。
So, everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
A Kiowa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.