英会話タイムトライアル
Let's get started with the fifth day of our special week.
It's day 20 for the month of September.
Hi, everyone.
I'm Steve Sareisi.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore.
Thanks for joining us.
スペシャルウィーク5日目です。
今日はこちらのコーナーをたっぷりお楽しみください。
What's?
What's this song?
まずはヒントをもとに、今日練習する歌の曲名を当ててみましょう。
作詞作曲したのはアメリカのミュージシャンプリンスです。
アイルランド出身のシンガーがカバーし大ヒットしました。
And here's another hint. I'll hum the chorus part a little.
So now, can you guess what the song is?
今日練習する曲は
Nothing Compares to You
アイルランド出身の歌手、シェネイド・オーカーナーが1990年にカバーした曲です。
愛する人と別れた悲しみと、その人がかけがえのない存在であることを歌っています。
Let's check out Sinead O'Connor's big hit, Nothing Compares to You.
I go out every night and sleep all day
Since you took your love
Since you've been gone I can do whatever I want
I can see whomever I choose
I can eat my dinner in a fancy restaurant
But nothing, I said nothing can take away this blues
Cause nothing compares
それでは、これからこの曲をジェニーさんと一緒に練習していきましょう。
OK, let's try singing this together.
I'll sing the first part, so now you can just listen to me.
Here we go!
It's been seven hours and fifteen days
Since you took your love away
Okay, now it's your turn.
You can sing along with me this time.
Here we go.
It's been seven hours and fifteen days
Since you took your love away
Okay, great. Now, here's the next part. Just listen.
I'll go out every night and sleep all day
Since you took your love away
Okay, it's your turn to sing along with me. Let's go.
I'll go out every night and sleep all day, since you took your love away.
Okay, you're doing great. Now here's the next part. First, just listen.
Since you've been gone, I can do whatever I want.
I can see whomever I choose.
Okay, it's your turn. Sing along with me.
Since you've been gone, I can do whatever I want.
I can see whomever I choose.
All right.
Are you ready for the last part?
Okay, listen first.
I can eat my dinner in a fancy restaurant
But nothing, I said nothing can take away this blues
Cause nothing compares, nothing compares to you
Okay, do you feel ready for the final part? Let's sing it together.
I can eat my dinner in a fancy restaurant, but nothing, I said nothing can take away the
Cause nothing compares, nothing compares to you.
All right, everyone, you did it.
How did it feel?
Okay, now let's sing the whole part that we practiced today.
Just have fun with it.
That's the most important part.
Here we go.
It's been seven hours and fifteen days
Since you took your love away
I go out every night and sleep all day
Since you took your love away.
Since you've been gone, I can do whatever I want.
I can see whomever I choose.
I can eat my dinner in a fancy restaurant, but nothing, I said nothing can take away these blues, cause nothing compares, nothing compares to you.
All right. I really enjoyed singing with you all.
Great job, everyone, and great job this month.
今月は4週間。お疲れ様でした。
さて、英語でつながる船の旅はまだまだ続きます。
来月向かうのは…
アイルランド!
そうです。今日紹介したシンガー、シェネイド・オカーナーの出身地でもあるアイルランドへと向かいます。
We're looking forward to seeing you next month.
それでは、今日練習した曲、Nothing Compares to Youを聞きながらお別れしましょう。
So, get on board, and let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
いいかいわタイムトライアル。
バイバイ!
Since you've been gone, I can do whatever I want.
I can see whomever I choose
I can eat my dinner in a fancy restaurant
But nothing, I said nothing can take away this blues
Cause nothing compares