Let's get started with Day 10 for the month of October.
Hi, everyone. I'm Steve Sarese, and here's your conversation partner around the Atlantic.
Hi, everyone. I'm Nora Kennedy.
Just try to complete the conversation with me today in your own words.
Here we go!
ラジオを通して英語で模擬会話をしましょう。
英語でつながる船の旅。
今月はアイロランドに行きます。
And do you remember our theme?
Cuisine together in Ireland.
味わい深い料理の会話。
So, let's check out today's scene.
Imagine this.
We go to the rolling hills of Ireland for a picnic.
あなたは今日、ノラさん、そしてノラさんの友人数人と一緒にピクニックに行くことになりました。
場所はきれいな景色が広がるアイロランドの丘の上です。
It's a potluck, so everyone brings one dish.
今回はポトラック、料理持ち寄りのピクニックです。
Just tell us about what you brought.
Is it something Japanese?
Yes.
あなたは何を持ってきたのか聞かれるので、料理を自由に想像しましょう。
そして、その料理には何が入っているかなども聞かれます。
Did you picture the situation?
それでは、野良さんの英語の問いかけに対して、ポーズの間に英語で返答しましょう。
今週練習した表現を使ってみてもOKですよ。
Ready, start!
Oh, you made it. Say hi to everyone.
さあ、野良さんの友人たちに元気よく挨拶しましょう。どうぞ。
ジア・グッチ。
Well, help yourself to some Irish food.
Shepherd's pie, soda bread, or Irish stew here.
Are you a meat-eater?
Okay, start with this.
Oh, I see you brought a dish for us.
What dish did you bring?
何の料理を持ってきたのか、自由に答えましょう。
どうぞ。
It sounds good.
So, what's in it?
Ah, I think I know of that dish. It's not very spicy, right?
Let's pass around paper plates. And for your dish, should we use a serving fork or serving chopsticks?
OK. Everyone, enjoy! And would you like to try Irish Soda Bread?
Ireland's traditional bread, Soda Bread, has been recommended.
Let's say a few words. Here you go.
OK. Time's up.
How many times did you reply?
So, what do people say in Japan when you tell them you're from Ireland?
Well, they always say,
Oh, you're from Ireland. It must be so cold.
Oh, it's not cold in Ireland?
No, it's...
Actually, even though Ireland is more northerly than Hokkaido,
it's actually quite mild, and it never snows.
Really?
Yeah.
Hokkaido yori Ireland no hou ga i do ga takai no ni yuki ga furanai n desu ne.
Soshite soko made samuku nai to Nora-san ga oshattemasu ne.
Soredewa, Nora-san to boku de kyou no kaiwa o shite mimasu.
Boku no hento o cheku shite sanko ni shite mite kudasai.
Steve will show you one way to reply.
Listen carefully.
Oh, you made it.
Say hi to everyone.
Hi, everyone. I'm Steve.
Well, help yourself to some Irish food.
Shepherd's pie, soda bread, or Irish stew here.
Are you a meat eater?
Yes, I have meat all the time.
Okay, start with this.
Oh, I see you brought a dish for us.
What dish did you bring?
I brought stir-fried noodles.
This dish is called yakisoba.
It sounds good.
So, what's in it?
It has vegetables, pork, and noodles in it.
And you could put some nori on it, if you like.
Ah, I see.
i think i know of that dish it's not very spicy right right but you can add this seasoning called
shchimi it has a mix of seven spices in it let's pass around paper plates and for your dish
should we use a serving fork or serving chopsticks
i usually use chopsticks but a serving fork might be easier for everyone okay
Everyone, enjoy! And would you like to try Irish soda bread?
Oh, I've never had soda bread. What's in it?
Okay, did you understand our conversation?
それでは、最後にもう一度今日の模擬会話に挑戦です。
僕の返答例と同じ答え方ではなく、自分なりの返答できるかどうかチャレンジしてください。
Do your best, everyone. Ready, start!
Oh, you made it! Say hi to everyone.
Geoguch! Well, help yourself to some Irish food.
Shepherd's pie, soda bread, or Irish stew here.
Are you a meat-eater?
Okay, start with this.
Oh, I see you brought a dish for us.
What dish did you bring?
It sounds good.
So, what's in it?
ah i think i know of that dish it's not very spicy right
let's pass around paper plates and for your dish should we use a serving fork or serving chopsticks
Okay. Everyone, enjoy.
And would you like to try Irish soda bread?
Time's up.
Okay. You did much better the second time. Great job.
How was your second challenge?
Next week.
We're going to a nice restaurant in the capital of Ireland, Dublin.
That's right.
来週の金曜日は野良さんとアイルランドの首都、ダブリンのレストランに行きます。
I'm really looking forward to it.
OK, everyone. Get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
Ekaewa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.