Let's get started with Day 14 for the month of October.
Hi, everyone. I'm Steve Sarese.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore. Thanks for joining us.
It's Thursday. Let's practice the phrases we learned this week.
And we'll get you ready for actual conversations.
All right, let's get started.
Express.
Create.
Reply.
Let's do some warming up.
Step 1. Express.
Ima kara Jenny-san ga konshuu rinshu shita hyougen o random ni itte kuremasu no de,
nani mo minai de zenbu ripiito dekiru ka challenge shite mite kudasai.
So, try to repeat each phrase after me.
And copy my intonation.
Okay, here we go.
This Irish restaurant is charming.
Our table is over there.
I like the music and the atmosphere.
Let's have a seat.
Today's specials are written on that board.
How hungry are you?
I'm pretty hungry.
All right. Did you express all those phrases quickly and smoothly?
And now, let's move on to the next step.
Step 2. Create.
Next, let's use the phrases we learned this week and create some original sentences.
Here's the first one.
Saisho ni nani nani wa ikaga desu ka?
To start, would you like nani nani?
You can imagine you're at a restaurant or you're entertaining someone at home.
Are you ready?
To start, would you like...
Go ahead.
Okay.
Now, let's check out Jenny's sentence.
Jenny?
To start, would you like an appetizer?
Good.
Okay.
Now, try to make one more with
To start, would you like something?
Dewa ikimashou.
To start, would you like...
Go ahead.
では2つ目のフレーズです。
最初は何々にします。
To start, I'll have 〇〇。
Now you're ordering.
最初に何を注文するか伝えましょう。
Ready?
To start, I'll have...
Go ahead.
Good!
Now it's Jenny's turn.
To start, I'll have the cheese platter.
That's a good one.
Moriabase in English is often platter.
For example, cheese no moriabase, cheese platter.
Jenny said, to start, I'll have the cheese platter.
All right.
Use your imagination and order something with this phrase.
To start, I'll have...
Go ahead.
Very good.
では、三つ目の表現に行きましょう。
この料理には何々がついています。
This dish comes with 〇〇。
So imagine you're at a restaurant and you tell a friend,
This dish comes with something.
Are you ready to create?
This dish comes with...
Go ahead.
Okay, let's see what Jenny creates.
This dish comes with a dessert.
That's a good one.
それではもう一度文を作りましょう。
It's your turn again.
This dish comes with...
Go ahead.
Okay, now let's move on to our final step.
Step 3. Reply.
Next, we'll practice something important.
You'll reply in English to some questions.
Just use your own words.
Here's the first one.
想像してください。
あなたは僕と朝食を取ることになりました。
レストランにやってきたあなたに声をかけます。
You made it to the restaurant.
Was it hard to find?
お店は見つけにくかったですか?と聞いていますので、
You can start with yes or no, and then add one sentence.
Are you ready?
You made it to the restaurant. Was it hard to find?
Go ahead.
Okay, let's check out Jenny's sample reply.
You made it to the restaurant. Was it hard to find?
Not really. Sorry if I kept you waiting.
First, Jenny said, not really.
Yesでも noでもなく、それほどではありませんでした。
Not really.
And then she said, sorry if I kept you waiting.
お待たせしていたなら、すみません。
Okay, it's your turn to try one more time.
I'll ask the same question.
Try to reply within the time limit.
Here we go.
You made it to the restaurant.
Was it hard to find?
Okay, let's go to the second question.
朝食を注文する前に、
飲み物を注文しようと提案します。
To start, would you like something to drink?
自由に返答してください。
Are you ready?
To start, would you like something to drink?
Go ahead.
Okay, let's check out a sample reply.
To start, would you like something to drink?
I'll just have some water for now.
とりあえず in English is for now.
So, Jenny said.
I'll just have some water, tori-aizu, for now.
Alright, it's your turn to try again.
I'll ask the same question.
To start, would you like something to drink?
Good job!
Let's go to the last question.
どれくらいお腹が空いているか聞きます。
How hungry are you?
いや、いろいろ食べ物の話してますから、きっとお腹すいてますね。
You must be hungry.
Because we've been talking about food, right, Jenny?
Yeah.
Actually, I'm getting hungry, too.
Me, too.
Okay, so here's a good question.
自分なりに答えてください。
How hungry are you?
Go ahead.
Okay.
Let's see how Jenny replies.
How hungry are you?
I'm pretty hungry, but I usually don't eat that much.
わりとおなかすいています。
I'm pretty hungry.
And then Jenny said,
But I usually don't eat that much.
ふだんはそんなにたくさん食べないですよ。
OK.
You can use that phrase or another,
but just reply in your own words.
And let's try this one more time.
How hungry are you?
Okay, time's up.
Great job today, everyone.
All right, you're ready for tomorrow's conversation.
It's Taiwacaroke.
You're going to a charming restaurant in Ireland.
And you'll have a full Irish breakfast.
今週練習した表現をぜひ明日使ってみてくださいね。
Sounds like a fun one.
So everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
英会話タイムトライアル。
Bye-bye.