Let's get started with Day 15 for the month of October.
Hi, everyone. I'm Steve Sarese, and here's your conversation partner around the Atlantic.
Hi, everyone. I'm Nora Kennedy. Let's have a conversation in Ireland.
All right. We'll finish our month with this.
Taiwa Karaoke. Around the Atlantic.
ラジオを通して英語で模擬会話をしましょう。
英語でつながる船の旅。
あなたはアイロランドに来ています。
ということで早速、今日の会話の場面を確認しましょう。
Imagine this.
Today, you and I are going to have breakfast at a nice restaurant in Dublin.
It's the capital of Ireland.
あなたは今日、ノラさんとアイルランドの首都ダブリンにあるレストランで朝食をとることになりました。
It's not an easy restaurant to find.
It's not in most guidebooks.
But the food is terrific, and the atmosphere is lovely.
そこは穴場のレストランで、雰囲気も良く料理も美味しいようですよ。
This morning...
We are having something very Irish.
A full Irish breakfast.
Irelandならではの朝食セット
Full Irish breakfastを注文しましょう。
Did you picture the situation?
それでは、野良さんの英語の問いかけに対して
ポーズの間に自由に英語で返答しましょう。
今週練習したフレーズを使ってみてもOKですよ。
So, try to have
seven-turn conversation. We'll enjoy
a full Irish breakfast. Ready?
Start!
You made it to the restaurant. Was it hard to find?
It's great to see you.
Have a seat. How do you like this restaurant?
restaurant no can so she took auto
to start
we'd you like something to drink
okay here's a menu
how hungry are you
we can order on a cart
But I like the full Irish breakfast here.
せっかくなので、アイルランドならではの朝食セットを注文しましょう。
The full Irish breakfast comes with black pudding, baked beans, mushrooms, grilled tomatoes and eggs.
How would you like your eggs?
卵はどのように調理してもらいたいか聞かれました。
自由に答えましょう。
どうぞ。
All right.
I'm getting hungry.
一言返しましょう。
どうぞ。
Time's up.
Did you try to reply each time?
アイルランドの食べ物についてノラさんに聞きましょう。
Today we talked about a full Irish breakfast.
Yes, you absolutely have to have a full Irish breakfast when you go to Ireland.
And it's pretty much the same everywhere, but there are some regional variations.
アイルランドに行ったらぜひフルアイルランドの食べ物を体験してください。
How about your hometown?
Can you have full Irish breakfast in your hometown?
Sure.
We would have a full Irish breakfast with black pudding and white pudding.
I see.
By the way, you said your hometown is New Mullet?
No.
Bell Mullet.
My apologies.
No problem.
Your hometown is Bell Mullet?
Yeah.
What kind of food is your hometown famous for?
Well, because it's by the sea, there's lots of delicious seafood like oysters or lobsters.
But also, because the lambs in the spring, when they're born, they eat the grass by the seaside, which has a kind of salty flavour.
The grass has salt in it because it's by the sea?
The seaside, right?
So, this kind of lamb is called salt marsh lamb and it has a lovely, naturally salty taste.
Wow.
That's a wonderful story.
So there's a natural salty seasoning to the lamb.
食べてみたいですね。
さあ、それでは、英会話のトレーニングに戻りましょう。
ノラさんと僕で今日の会話をしてみます。
僕のフルアイリッシュブレックフェスについての
返答をチェックして参考にしてください。
Steve will show you one way to reply.
Listen carefully.
You made it to the restaurant. Was it hard to find?
Not really. Sorry if I kept you waiting.
It's great to see you. Have a seat.
How do you like this restaurant?
This Irish restaurant is charming.
To start, would you like something to drink?
I'll just have some water for now.
OK. Here's a menu.
How hungry are you?
I'm pretty hungry, but I usually don't eat that much.
We can order à la carte, but I like the full Irish breakfast here.
We're in Ireland, so we might as well try a full Irish breakfast.
The full Irish breakfast comes with black pudding, baked beans, mushrooms, grilled tomatoes and eggs.
How would you like your eggs?
May I have my eggs sunny-side up?
All right. I'm getting hungry.
Me too. I'm so excited to try those dishes.
Okay. Did you understand our conversation?
最後に、野良さんが、I'm getting hungry.
これは質問ではない問いかけですので、自分なりに答えてください。
僕は、Me too.
You can stop there, but if you can, please tell us how much you're looking forward to it.
I'm so excited to try those dishes.
Finally, let's try the Mogi conversation again today.
Please challenge yourself to see if you can give your own answer.
Do your best, everyone.
Ready, start!
You made it to the restaurant!
Was it hard to find?
It's great to see you. Have a seat.
How do you like this restaurant?
To start, would you like something to drink?
Okay, here's a menu.
How hungry are you?
We can order a la carte, but I like the full Irish breakfast here.
Since we're here, let's order a set of breakfasts unique to Ireland.
The full Irish breakfast comes with black pudding, baked beans, mushrooms, grilled tomatoes and eggs.
How would you like your eggs?
All right. I'm getting hungry.
Okay, time's up.
Great job this month, everyone.
Did you enjoy our journey around Ireland?
I enjoyed learning about Ireland from you. Thanks, Nora.
My pleasure, Steve.
さて、英語でつながる船の旅はまだまだ続きます。
来月向かうのは、
We're going to Iceland!
来月は野良さんとアイスランドに行きますよ。
You'll really improve your conversation skills there.
And everyone, get on board!
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
Eikaiwa Time Trial!
Bye-bye!