Let's get started with Day 10 for the month of October.
Hi, everyone. I'm Steve Sarese, and here's your conversation partner around the Atlantic.
Hi, everyone. I'm Nora Kennedy.
Just try to complete the conversation with me today in your own words.
Here we go!
Taiwa Harake. Around the Atlantic.
ラジオを通して英語で模擬会話をしましょう
英語でつながる船の旅
今月はアイロランドに行きます
And do you remember our theme?
Cuisine together in Ireland
味わい深い料理の会話
So, let's check out today's scene
Imagine this
We go to the rolling hills of Ireland
For a picnic with friends.
あなたは今日、ノラさん、そしてノラさんの友人数人と一緒にピクニックに行くことになりました。
場所はきれいな景色が広がるアイロランドの丘の上です。
It's a potluck, so everyone brings one dish.
今回はポトラック、料理持ち寄りのピクニックです。
Just tell us about what you brought.
Is it something Japanese?
あなたは何を持ってきたのか聞かれるので、料理を自由に想像しましょう。
そして、その料理には何が入っているかなども聞かれます。
Did you picture the situation?
それでは、野良さんの英語の問いかけに対して、ポーズの間に英語で返答しましょう。
今週練習した表現を使ってみてもOKですよ。
Ready, start!
Oh, you made it. Say hi to everyone.
さあ、ノラスターの友人たちに元気よく挨拶しましょう。どうぞ。
ジア・グッチ。
Well, help yourself to some Irish food.
Shepherd's pie, soda bread, or Irish stew here.
Are you a meat eater?
Okay, start with this.
Oh, I see you brought a dish for us.
What dish did you bring?
何の料理を持ってきたのか、自由に答えましょう。
どうぞ。
It sounds good.
So, what's in it?
I think I know of that dish. It's not very spicy, right?
Let's pass around paper plates.
And for your dish, should we use a serving fork or serving chopsticks?
OK. Everyone, enjoy.
And would you like to try Irish soda bread?
Ireland's traditional bread, soda bread, was recommended.
Let's say a word. Please.
OK. Time's up.
How many times did you reply?
It's okay if it's not the first time.
After this, Nora and I will try this conversation.
And lastly, there's one more chance.
Before that, let's talk a little about Ireland with Nora.
So, what do people say in Japan when you tell them you're from Ireland?
Well, they always say,
Oh, you're from Ireland. It must be so cold.
Oh, it's not cold in Ireland?
No.
Actually, even though Ireland is more northerly than Hokkaido, it's actually quite mild, and it never snows.
Really?
Yeah.
Hokkaidoよりアイルランドの方が緯度が高いのに雪が降らないんですね。
そしてそこまで寒くないと野良さんがおっしゃってますね。
それでは野良さんと僕で今日の会話をしてみます。
僕の返答をチェックして参考にしてみてください。
Steve will show you one way to reply. Listen carefully.
Oh, you made it. Say hi to everyone.
Hi, everyone. I'm Steve. Geoguch.
Geoguch. Well, help yourself to some Irish food.
Shepherd's pie, soda bread, or Irish stew here.
Are you a meat-eater?
Yes, I have meat all the time.
OK, start with this.
Oh, I see you brought a dish for us.
What dish did you bring?
I brought stir-fried noodles.
This dish is called yakisoba.
It sounds good.
So, what's in it?
It has vegetables, pork and noodles in it.
And you could put some nori on it if you like.
Ah, I think I know of that dish. It's not very spicy, right?
Right, but you can add this seasoning called shchimi. It has a mix of seven spices in it.
Let's pass around paper plates. And for your dish, should we use a serving fork or serving chopsticks?
I usually use chopsticks, but a serving fork might be easier for everyone.
OK. Everyone, enjoy. And would you like to try Irish soda bread?
Oh, I've never had soda bread. What's in it?
OK. Did you understand our conversation?
So, let's try again today's Mogi conversation.
It's not the same answer as my reply.
自分なりのヘントできるかどうかチャレンジしてください。
Do your best, everyone.
Ready, start!
Oh, you made it!
Say hi to everyone!
ジアグッチ!
Well, help yourself to some Irish food.
Shepherd's pie, soda bread...
Irish stew here are you a meat-eater
okay start with this oh I see you brought a dish for us what dish did you
bring it sounds good so what's in it
I think I know of that dish. It's not very spicy, right?
Let's pass around paper plates.
And for your dish, should we use a serving fork or serving chopsticks?
Chopsticks.
OK. Everyone, enjoy.
And would you like to try Irish soda bread?
Time's up.
OK. You did much better the second time. Great job.
How was your second challenge?
Next week.
We're going to a nice restaurant in the capital of Ireland, Dublin.
That's right.
来週の金曜日は野良さんとアイルランドの首都、ダブリンのレストランに行きます。
I'm really looking forward to it.
OK, everyone. Get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
Eikaiwa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.